OK, so in this video,
let's talk about the iteration
burn down chart and the
iteration burnup chart, right?
Both of these are a type of information
radiator, right, or both of these are
charts that could be used as part of the
information radiator.
And both of these are specifically for
Aga.
Now the iteration burn down chart then,
right?
It's basically showing what work remains,
right, what work remains to be complete.
Now, first of all, before we talk about
this, remember in the agile world,
right, you have this term called the
definition of done.
And the definition of done is something
that the team and the product owner and
the team facilitator agrees to at the
release planning.
And definition of done
basically means that, you
know, what does it mean
for the work to be complete?
In the agile world, there's no such thing
as percentage of work complete.
Either the work is complete or it's not
complete.
There's none of this or we're 50% complete
or this task is 80% complete.
It's either 100% complete or it's 0%
complete.
Even if a task is 99% complete,
it means it's 0% complete.
If it does not meet that definition of
done, then it's not complete.
So what the iteration burn
down chart and the burnup chart is
basically showing is in
relation to that definition of done.
So what the burn down chart is showing,
what work remains, right?
Throughout a release, what work remains?
Right, so it's a very simple example then.
So you've got, let's say this
release is a seven-month release
from January to July and we
have 300 story points, right?
300 user stories, 300 story points to
implement during this release.
So the blue line here is, is our general
burn rate.
This is our planned burn rate.
We're going to be doing this many user
stories, right?
In a linear fashion,
these are how many user
stories we should be
implementing over time.
So for example, January, we start with 300
user stories.
In February, it looks like we should be,
we should have 250 left.
In March, we should have 200 left and so
on and so forth.
Just as a very simple example.
Now, that's the blue line.
The red line then is showing how have we
actually performed, what's actually left,
right?
And so we can see then
in February, right, we're
showing that there's
actually 275 users left.
In March, it's showing that there's,
what, maybe about 280, 250 users that's
left in March and so and so on and so
forth.
So on the onset, it looks like we might be
running into trouble.
We might be going behind schedule.
However, what the burn
down chart does not actually
show is a fact that user
stories can be added.
So this is just showing based on the
original plan, the original planned number
of user stories are original plan story
points.
So the iteration burn down chart is
specifically showing what work remains,
what work remains to be complete.
There's another chart called the iteration
burn-up chart, right?
So this chart here, the iteration burn up
chart.
And this is showing how much work has
actually been accomplished, what has
actually been completed, what's actually
been accomplished.
And this chart will show work that has
been added.
Remember, user stories can be added at any
time.
So this takes into consideration these
additional user stories.
So in January, our original plan was we
have 300 user stories, 300 stories.
points that need to be implemented.
However, we can see by February they've
been increased to maybe, you know,
325 user stories.
We've got more user stories, right?
In fact, by April, it
looks like we're up to
350 user stories because
they've been added.
So based on that, it's showing what we've
actually accomplished.
And so that's what the iteration burn up
chart is showing, how much work has been
completed, what we've actually
accomplished.
So these are two types of charts that are
specifically for Agile, specifically for
the Agile World, iteration burn down
chart, iteration burn up chart.
And as I said, as part of the information
radiator, right, you may include,
or teams may include
the iteration burn down,
iteration burn up chart
to show their progress.